SAURABH RAYAKWAR

SUMMARY

Experienced Developer with a demonstrated history of working in the Information Technology and Services industry. Skilled in PHP, NodeJs, MongoDB and ElasticSearch. Strong engineering professional with a Bachelor of Technology (BTech) focused in Information Technology from Vellore Institute of Technology.

SKILLS

LANGUAGES : PHP / NodeJs / JAVA

FRAMEWORKS : LARAVEL / CODEIGNITER / SAILS JS / ORACLE ATG

DATABASES : MYSQL / POSTGRESQL / MONGO DB

TOOLS : SUPERSET / ORACLE ATG BCC / ELASTICSEARCH SENSE /SELENIUM

IDEs : ECLIPSE / SUBLIME / INTELLI-J

OS : UBUNTU 14.04 LTS / MacOS High Sierra

VERSIONING : GIT / TORTOISE SVN

EXPERIENCE

STYLABS, Mumbai - Software Developer

Nov 2016 - PRESENT

Improved and created systems with the expansion of the scope of the product i.e. StyFi

- Supported and enhanced existing product based on Opencart/PHP.
- Created system in PHP/Laravel & nodejs for onboarding of hyperlocal, local and national brands.
- Created system in nodejs for integration of existing product with multiple delivery service providers
- Implemented real time feedback system for the above systems using rocket chat.
- Data flow design, database design, peer code review using review board, code development using intellij IDE, Git, ElasticSearch etc.
- Implemented Apache Superset as part of Business Intelligence.
- Practiced agile through JIRA with 14 other developers

Nestopia, Mumbai — *Sr Backend Developer*

MARCH 2016 - NOV 2016

Nestopia is an interior designing firm and my attempt was to automate the process of interior designing through application of various technologies.

- Supported and enhanced existing product based on Codeigniter/PHP.
- Created system to help with registration of local interior designers with Nestopia.
- Porting of the back-end codebase from Codeigniter to Laravel 5.1.
- Data flow design, database design, peer code review using review board, code development using intellij IDE, Git, Query optimization, ElasticSearch etc.

Wodrob, Mumbai - Software Engineer

JUNE 2015 - MARCH 2016

WODROB offers personalised fashion recommendations across mediums and my attempt was to make it seamless through technology.

- Supported and enhanced existing product called Wodrob based on Laravel/PHP.
- Provided development and support in PHP for B2B marketplace called GoldBazzar, by WODROB.
- Implemented OAuth 2.0 for restful APIs
- Developed chrome extension for Wodrob users to be able to tag content on various websites

SapientNitro, Bengaluru - Associate L1

JULY 2013 - MARCH 2015

Worked on two multisite ATG projects where I gained knowledge of Oracle DB, Oracle ATG, ATG BCC and ATG Endeca.

- Created sites through BCC and also finalized and uploaded business related Labels, Config Keys etc through BCC.
- Developed in JAVA using EclipseIDE, built code through Jenkins while using tortoise SVN for version control.
- Developed for MyAccount and Checkout modules of the websites.
- Responsive email designing, code debugging, coordinate sprint meetings etc.
- Practiced agile in scrums of 21 days with 14 other developers

EDUCATION

VELLORE INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, Vellore - Bachelor of Technology

June 2009 - May 2013

- Received degree in Information Technology with CGPA of 9.11

MGM SR SEC SCHOOL, Bhilai — HSC

June 2007 - May 2009

- Received higher secondary examination certificate

PERSONAL INFORMATION

: 15.07.1991 DOB

GENDER : Male
FATHER'S NAME : Mr. Wasudev Rayakwar

MARITAL STATUS : Unmarried

PERMANENT ADDRESS: HIG-1/13 ADITYA NAGAR MPHB COLONY DURG 491001 C.G.

: 9769830695 PHONE